本集結束之后 敬請繼續關注
堡壘
解密檔案
《堡壘》前情提要
你跟你老公是怎么認識的
So, how did you and your husband meet?
我在那里開始接受記憶療法 當時凱爾也參加了同樣的項目
I started memory therapy there. Kyle was in the same program.
在堡壘被摧毀期間
During Citadel's collapse,
我的門生卡特斯賓塞 把這個箱子藏了起來
I ordered my protégé Carter Spence to take the case underground.
這個箱子是唯一 能定位幸存堡壘特工的技術
He says it's the only tech that can locate any Citadel agents who might still be alive.
實在是抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你是納迪亞
- You're Nadia.
- 并不是 - 你跟我一樣也是間諜
- No. You are a spy like me.
- 這是… - 是你
That's... You.
如果我回家 他們會找到我 只有阻止他們 我才能保護家人
If I go home, they're gonna find me. Stopping them, that's how I protect my family.
我找到她了 她什么都記得
- I found her. - She remembers everything.
- 是女的  - 是的
- She? - Yeah.
她叫納迪亞
Her name's Nadia.
私人模式已啟動
Private mode initiated.
貨物怎么樣了
- 她還知道什么  - 她知道的并不多
What else did she know? Not a lot.
我們會把事情搞定 然后我就回你身邊
We're gonna figure this out, and then I'm coming back to you, okay?
- 跟我聊聊他吧 - 誰
Tell me about him. - Who?
梅森 他是什么樣的人
- Mason, who was he?
沒辦法跟你說 我跟他關系沒那么近
Couldn't tell you. We weren't that close.
- 從來沒有私人交情 - 從來沒有
- We never got personal. - Never?
凱恩 我很驚訝 你居然會愛上一個
I am surprised, Kane, that you, of all people,
曾經摧毀了堡壘的女人
would carry a torch for the woman who brought Citadel to its knees.
數據傳輸完成 趕快出來
Transfer's complete. Get out of there.
你到底在說什么
The hell are you talking about?
是你的女友 納迪亞
It was your girl Nadia.
是你嗎
Was it you?
這是布瑞爾 對吧
That's Brielle, right?
你愛的女人
The woman you love,
她還活著
she's alive.
不會吧
- No.
她叫艾比
- Her name is Abby,
她嫁給了梅森凱恩
and she's married to Mason Kane.
我是特工卡特斯賓塞
This is Agent Carter Spence.
曼提柯爾正在接近我的位置
Manticore's closing in on my location.
這可能是我最后一次通訊
This might be my last transmission.
媽的
Shit.
我知道他在哪
I know where he is.
摩洛哥
曼提柯爾暗點
我們要大開殺戒了
So we're about to kill a bunch of people?
你已經不是第一次殺人了 親愛的
Not your first time, love.
走吧 快點
Now, come on.
（阿拉伯語） 我正在前往D區
I'm heading to D block.
拉響警報
Hit the alarm!
快趴下
Down!
我沒子彈了 掩護我
I'm out! Cover me!
- 掩護我 - 好的
Cover me!
媽的
Fuck!
還是我掩護你吧
Or I'll cover you.
梅森
Mason?
卡特
Carter.
我們會把你救出去的
We're gonna get you out of here.
我們走
Let's go.
別過來
Just stay back.
就是你干的
You did this.
我干了什么
What did I do?
堡壘
第一季第四集
本WEB版外掛字幕由  風吹來的那片云  雙語合并
巴黎 十年前
今天太有意思了
Well, this has been fun.
是啊
Yeah.
巴黎向來都很有意思
Paris always is.
“向來”
Always is?
你不會以為你是唯一一個 陪我來過巴黎的男人吧
You can't possibly believe you're the only man I've come to Paris with.
那倒是 但昨晚很顯然…
No, but last night was obviously...
- 質量很高 - 很高
It was up there. Up there.
能排進前五
Top five.
另外四位是間諜嗎
And the other four? Are they spies?
拜托 凱恩 我可不會宣揚自己的風流史
Mm. Come on, Kane. I don't kiss and tell.
談了很久嗎
They last long?
沒有一個長久的
They never do.
你談過戀愛嗎
You ever been in love?
你這算是什么問題
What kind of question is that?
真誠的問題
An honest one.
沒談過
No.
我嚇到你了嗎
Do I scare you?
你為什么會嚇到我
Now, why would you scare me?
- 因為我開始看穿你了 - 是嗎
- Because I'm starting to see you. - Oh, are you?
看穿你的面具
See past the mask.
什么面具
- What mask?
你有很多面具
- Oh, there are dozens.
這為什么會嚇到我呢
And why would that scare me?
我還不知道
I don't know yet.
我要給隊伍里 擴充一位新的一級行動員
I'm bringing a new Tier-One to the team.
格雷斯批準了
Grace approved.
- 格雷斯什么時候批準的  - 今天早上
- When did Grace approve? - This morning.
你今天早上跟格雷斯聯系了
You spoke to Grace this morning?
你應該知道除了咱倆的“任務” 我還有別的任務吧
You know I have other missions besides ours, right?
我當時去哪了
- Where was I?
不知道 可能在吃法式長棍面包 墜入愛河
- I don't know. Eating baguettes? - Falling in love?
她很聰明
She's brilliant.
再說了 我們需要她 她以前在精英小隊跟著我干過
Plus we need her. She worked for me on Bravo Team.
這是類似于將死之人的愿望嗎
This like a Make-A-Wish thing?
我愿意用性命相信她
I trust her with my life.
她救過我的命
She saved it once.
她叫塞萊斯特格雷厄姆 你會愛上她的
Her name is Celeste Graham, and you are gonna love her.
既然她是你的朋友
Well, if she's a friend of yours,
那我肯定會恨她
I'm sure I'll hate her.
堡壘總部
注定躲不過
I mean, it was bound to happen.
- 是嗎  - 只不過是時間早晚的問題
- Just a matter of time. - Was it?
這是我們的新一級行動員嗎
- This our new Tier-One?
梅森 這位是塞萊斯特格雷厄姆
Mason, meet Celeste Graham.
你就是救過她一條命的人
You're the person that saved her life.
就是我
I am.
她跟我說 我會愛你的
She told me I'm gonna love you.
你不會的
You won't.
任務日：01
她能應付得了
She can handle it.
她并不能
She can't.
“她”可是就坐在這里
She is right here.
她的一級許可證 是什么時候獲批的 36小時前嗎
Her Tier-One clearance went through, what, 36 hours ago?
別這樣 梅森 這算什么 刁難新人嗎
Oh, come on, Mason. What is this? Haze week?
這是你們特有的前戲嗎
Is this your version of foreplay?
安德斯和戴維克 經營著一家殘酷的犯罪企業
Anders and Davik run a brutal criminal enterprise.
- 我知道他們是誰 - 我覺得你并不知道
- I know who they are. - I don't think you do.
來自阿姆斯特丹的希爾杰兩兄弟
The Silje brothers out of Amsterdam.
他們統領著各類罪犯
They rule the city's underbelly.
販賣毒品 軍火交易 賣淫團伙
Drug running, arms dealing, prostitution rings.
他們已經開始擴張了
They've started to expand.
戴維克是打手 安德斯是軍師
Davik is the muscle. Anders is the brains.
他要危險得多
He's far more dangerous.
劍橋大學畢業生 一直致力于開發戰爭技術
He's a Cambridge grad who's been developing war technology
并將其賣給出價最高的人
and selling it to the highest bidder.
我們最近拿到了 安德斯最新創作的部分示意圖
We recently retrieved a partial schematic of Anders's latest creation.
他喜歡稱之為奧茲鑰匙
He likes to call it the Oz Key.
“奧茲鑰匙”
- "The Oz Key"? - If he completes it,
他一旦完成 奧茲鑰匙 將能夠黑進全國的基礎設施
the Oz Key would be able to hack an entire nation's infrastructure.
運輸 緊急服務 軍隊 武器
Transit, emergency services, army, weapons.
他們可以劫持整個國家
They could take a whole country hostage.
別說不可能 他就是想讓你以為不可能
Don't say it's impossible. He wants you to say it's impossible.
不可能
It's impossible.
單說計算能力 需要新罕布什爾州 那么大的服務器場才能滿足
The computational power alone would require a server farm the size of New Hampshire. Not to mention the fact that the source data-- which,
更不用說幾乎是核心的源數據了
if I understand you correctly, is basically everything--
這將需要數千艾字節
that would entail thousands of exabytes of data.
需要整個馬薩諸塞州 才能存得下那些二進制的數據
So I guess you could take over Massachusetts while you're at it to house all those ones and zeroes.
所以 除非 阿姆斯特丹的面積大幅增加
So, unless Amsterdam's gotten a whole lot bigger than I remember,
否則安德斯在完成奧茲鑰匙之前 還有很長一段路要走
your boy Anders has a long way to go before he gets his Oz Key.
- 她挺聰明的 - 她比你聰明
She's smart. - Smarter than you.
- 但她錯了 - 我沒錯
- But she's wrong. I'm not wrong.
你錯了 但你確實很有說服力
You are, but you were convincing.
這也就是她很完美的原因
Which is what makes her perfect.
而且 她還有個雙胞胎兄弟 就像安德斯一樣
Plus... she has a twin brother. Just like Anders.
- 還有一個跟你一樣的人  - 大衛
There's another one of you out there? - David.
- 你們關系近嗎  - 一提他我就來氣
- You close? - Hate him with a passion.
那看來你們關系很近
- Mm, so you're close.
形影不離
Inseparable.
- 而且我說對了 - 我可沒那么說
- And I'm right. - I didn't say that.
雖然你從不承認 但我總是對的
Well, you never do, but I always am.
我以前在守誓者民兵組織當過臥底
I've been undercover before with the Oath Keepers.
當了多久
- How long for?
- 三個星期 - 三個星期
- Three weeks. Three weeks.
在臥底方面 納迪亞在精英小隊里教過你什么
What did Nadia teach you over in Bravo about going undercover?
她教我 當臥底的關鍵 是學會如何圓謊
She taught me that the key to being undercover is learning how to maintain the lie.
納迪亞認為好間諜一定要擅長撒謊
Mm. Nadia thinks a great spy has to be a great liar.
- 確實是 - 不是的
- They do. - No.
優秀的間諜需要說真話
A great spy needs to tell the truth.
但首先 你必須要“消失”
But first, you have to disappear.
任務日：03
你需要做到照著鏡子 覺得鏡中的人與自己判若兩人
You need to look in the mirror and see an entirely different person looking back.
阿姆斯特丹
你能在鐵面酒吧找到安德斯
You'll find Anders at the Ironside Bar.
那里是他兄弟二人 共同經營的洗錢前沿陣地之一
It's one of the laundering fronts he runs with his brother.
看來你是一位工程師啊
We got an engineer over here. You must be a mad man,
你肯定是個瘋子 我絕對會離你遠點
I'm definitely staying away from you.
我叫安德斯
I'm Anders.
我叫布瑞爾
- Brielle.
布瑞爾
別想方設法試圖讓他愛上你
Don't worry about making him fall in love with you.
而是你要愛上他
You need to fall in love with him.
找到他值得你愛的地方 這樣才能感覺真實
Find things to love about him, so it'll feel real.
任務日：19
當臥底的時候不能撒謊
You can't lie when you're undercover.
安德斯和戴維克這種人 立馬就能知道你在撒謊
Men like Anders and Davik will smell it
一旦被他們發現 他們會殺了你
from across the room. And if they do, they'll bury you alive.
要想讓他們相信你的謊言
The only way they're gonna believe your lie
首先你自己要信
is if you do.
你跟他們所說的一切 都要成為你自認為的真話
Everything you tell them has to become your truth.
你要騙自己
You have to lie to yourself.
任務日：46
你的任務是 收集關于奧茲鑰匙的所有情報
Your mission is to gather all intel on the Oz Key.
不惜任何代價
Do whatever it takes.
盡可能接近
Get as close as you can.
這曲子真好聽 你在創作新歌
It's a beautiful melody. You creating a new song?
我在試著創作
I'm trying.
那你又在創作什么
What about you? What are you creating?
你看到我給那個東西 不斷地寫代碼 重寫代碼了嗎
You see me writing and rewriting the code for that thing.
那是什么
What is it?
這取決于你問誰
Depends on who you ask.
你想讓它變成什么
What do you want it to be?
我只想要你
I just want you.
你已經擁有我了
You already have me.
最困難的部分在于 要牢記你為什么會在那里
The hardest part is gonna be remembering why you're there.
要牢記那不是你的人生
That it's not actually your life.
我會一直拴著你的
I will keep you tethered.
你每周都要跟我報平安 給我打電話
Every week you check in with me.
我會提醒你什么才是真實的
Call me. I will remind you what is real, what is true.
倫敦
我知道就在這里某個位置
I know it's back here somewhere.
我說過吧
Told you.
一點都不像個姑娘
Not very ladylike.
為什么現在說這個
Mm. Why start now?
你說服了德米特里
You had Dmitri convinced.
現在我們知道了希爾杰兩兄弟 在維也納跟誰合作
Now we know who the Silje brothers are working with in Vienna.
倫敦 維也納
London. Vienna.
看來咱倆這段高質量的相處時光 要謝謝安德斯和戴維克了
I guess we have Anders and Davik to thank for all of this quality time together.
那你穿著這條漂亮裙子 我該謝謝誰
Who do I have to thank for this dress?
塞萊斯特難以自拔了
Celeste's in over her head.
她已經失聯三個月了
She's been dark for three months.
沒有報平安 也沒有回應我的信號彈
No check-ins, no click-backs to any of my flares.
但是全面攻破
But a full breach? It's too soon.
有點太早了吧
You know what it's like on the inside.
你也知道打入內部是什么樣的 可能有數不清的原因
There could be infinite reasons why she didn't check in.
如果是你去當臥底 我倒想看看這場好戲 可惜臥底是她
And if it were you in there I'd be willing to see how it plays out. But it's not you.
她跟我能力一樣強
She's just as capable as I am.
這正是我所擔心的
That's what I'm worried about.
卡特發現了一些異常情況
Carter picked up some anomalies.
什么異常情況
- What anomalies?
可能不嚴重 也可能極為嚴重
- Could be nothing. Could be everything.
我一直在調查她的背景
I've been digging deeper into her life.
她的雙胞胎兄弟大衛 有嚴重的賭博問題
Her twin brother David, he's got a serious gambling problem.
嚴重到賭資涉及六位數
Six figures serious.
他躲起來了 有些危險的人正在找他
He's holed up somewhere because some very dangerous people are after him.
所以呢
So?
當心愛的人處于危險之中時 人們就會做蠢事
You and I both know that people do stupid things when the ones they love are on the line.
她可以高價賣掉奧茲鑰匙
She can sell the Oz Key for a lot of money.
你這是在無中生有
You're seeing things that aren't there, Mason.
有消息稱 戴維克正在找買家
There's chatter on the wire that Davik's looking for a buyer.
所以奧茲鑰匙就算不能完全運轉 但也差不多了
So it's safe to assume the Oz Key is close to, if not fully operational.
- 只是時間早晚的問題… - 太早了
It's only a matter of time before... - It's too soon.
我知道她是你的朋友 但如果奧茲鑰匙被任何人拿到
- I know she's your friend but if anyone gets their hands on the Oz Key,
我們就無法掌控奧茲鑰匙 也失去了限制他們能力的機會
any chance of holding them at bay, any chance of keeping their power in check is gone.
我要派遣特別行動隊
I'm sending in an ops team.
在這地方放錢包 真奇怪
Odd place to store a purse.
安德斯肯定會很想你的
Anders is gonna miss you terribly.
我從特別行動隊那里收到了最新情況
I just got an update from the ops team.
雙方交火 我們有傷亡
Shots were exchanged and we've got casualties.
- 有多少  - 很多
- How many? - Enough.
天啊 塞萊斯特呢
Jesus. Celeste?
她還活著
She's alive.
被揍了 但還活著
Uh, beat up, but alive.
我們抓到了安德斯
We captured Anders,
戴維克不見了
Davik disappeared.
奧茲鑰匙呢
The Oz Key?
行動隊隊長說他們沒找到
Ops chief said they couldn't find it.
媽的
Fuck!
機密 她拿走了箱子
別提這件事 永遠別提
還剩30秒
Thirty seconds out.
醫療艙就位 迎接傷員進入
Secure med bay for incoming.
醫療艙待命
Med bay's on standby.
把她放在第二審訊室
Put her in Interrogation Two.
那他呢
What about him?
穩定他的狀態 讓他能開口
Stabilize him well enough to talk.
是誰的責任
Who's on point?
是我
I am.
戴維克不見了 奧茲鑰匙到底在哪
Davik's gone. And where the hell's the Oz Key?
我們著手去辦
We'll get under it.
把事情處理好
Clean this up.
- 我想進審訊室 - 不行
- I want in the box. - No.
- 我不是在請求 - 你倆關系太近了
- I'm not asking your permission. - You're too close.
- 梅森 - 你倆關系太近了
- Mason. - You're too close.
開始錄音
Begin recording.
這純屬胡鬧
This is bullshit.
名字和級別
- Name and classification.
這些都他媽的不重要了
- None of that fucking matters anymore, Mason.
系統 身份識別
- System Identify. - Identified.
- 一級行動員身份識別完畢… - 塞萊斯特格雷厄姆
- Tier-One Operator. Celeste Graham.
奧茲鑰匙在哪
Where is the Oz Key?
你他媽在逗我嗎
Are you fucking kidding me?
放松點 梅森
Easy, Mason.
你就不應該在這里跟我浪費時間
You shouldn't be in here wasting your time with me.
你應該出去機動 追捕戴維克
You should be out there, mobilizing, hunting Davik!
松開手銬
Remove restraints.
這是示好嗎 為了讓我心懷感激嗎
Is that supposed to be a gesture? To make me feel grateful?
塞萊斯特 你把奧茲鑰匙怎么樣了
What did you do with the Oz Key, Celeste?
我告訴過你了 在我的應急響應包里
I told you, it was in my go bag.
你的應急響應包是空的
Your go bag was empty.
特別行動隊清了場 他們只找到了這個
Ops cleaned the site. All they found was this.
這是假的
It's a fake.
里邊到底發生了什么事
What happened in there?
她在里邊嗎
Is she in there?
納迪亞 你在里邊嗎
Nadia, are you in there?
你覺得是我拿走了
You think I took it?
- 你要藏在鏡子后面嗎  - 坐下 塞萊斯特
You're gonna hide behind a mirror? Sit down, Celeste.
經歷了這么多事之后 你居然覺得是我拿的
After everything?! You think I'd do that?
去你媽的
Fuck you!
納迪亞 你能聽到嗎
Do you hear me, Nadia?
你當初就不應該讓我加入
You never should have brought me on.
過去三個月 你錯過了每一個接頭地點
For the last three months you've missed every one of your Live Drops.
是你違反協定在先
You were the one who broke protocol, Mason.
我還沒有準備好 你就派了特別行動隊
Sent an ops team before I was ready.
是你沒給我選擇的余地
You didn't give me a choice, did you?
你失聯了好幾周 我們不確定你是否還活著
You went dark for weeks. We didn't know if you were dead.
- 戴維克在哪  - 我把他安置在了地下室
- Where is Davik? - I secured him in the basement.
- 他不在地下室 - 我就是把他放在那里了
He wasn't there. That is where I left him.
你周圍的各種人和各種物件都不見了
People and things just disappearing around you left and right?
去死吧
Go to hell.
好吧
Okay.
那我們聊聊大衛
Let's talk about David.
我兄弟跟這有什么關系
What does my brother got to do with any of this?
八歲時 你繼父向你揮舞滾燙的熨斗 是你兄弟擋在了面前
At eight years old, he stepped in front of your stepdad swinging a hot iron at you.
是他挨打了 所以你幸免于難 那一次把他打得夠嗆
He took all the beatings so you didn't have to. And it fucked him up.
你想說什么
Where's this going?
我理解你一定深感愧疚
I understand the guilt you must have felt.
他為了保護你做了很大的犧牲
He sacrificed so much to protect you.
后來 在你繼父對他的各種行徑之后 你實在無力挽回他
Then after all your stepdad did to him, you couldn't fix him.
但你賣掉奧茲鑰匙 就能借此保全大衛的性命
But you sell the Oz Key and you can save his life,
支付他頭頂的賞金
pay the bounty on his head.
去你的 梅森
Fuck you, Mason.
你認識這棟樓嗎
You recognize this building?
放大8C單元
Zoom in to unit 8C.
那是誰
Who is that?
梅森 我兄弟 跟這件事一點關系都沒有
Mason, my brother has nothing to do with this.
但他卻處處跟你有關系
But he has everything to do with you.
你每周給他打一次電話 每個月給他寄八百美元
You call him once a week. You send him $800 a month.
即使在創業孵化器毫無收獲時 你也用了自己的積蓄給他付錢
Even when you were at the Incubator making nothing, you paid him out of your savings.
- 你兄弟是個廢人 - 閉嘴
Your brother seems like a fuckup to me. Shut up.
戰術小隊 武裝系統
Tac Unit, arm system.
系統已武裝
System armed.
- 住手 - 告訴我奧茲鑰匙在哪
- Stop. - Tell me where the Oz Key is.
我他媽真不知道
I don't know, I really don't fucking know.
你說你和兄弟關系很好 你倆間隔38秒先后出生 對嗎
You said you and your brother were close. What, 38 seconds apart?
- 鎖定目標 - 住手
Tac Unit, acquire target. Stop.
目標已鎖定
Target acquired.
你為了他而賣了奧茲鑰匙 不是嗎
You sold it for him, didn't you?
承認吧
Admit it.
- 買家是誰  - 誰也沒有
Who's your buyer? - Nobody.
最后一次機會
-- Last chance!
- 執… - 夠了
- Tac Unit, exec... - Enough.
你覺得你剛才是在干什么
The fuck do you think you were doing?
我沒準備把他干掉
I wasn't actually gonna take him out.
但你剛才聽起來是認真的
Oh, yeah? You sounded pretty convincing.
- 不能打斷審訊  - 剛才那根本不是審訊
You can't stop an interrogation! That wasn't a fucking interrogation!
那是在攻擊我們自己人
That was an assault on one of our own!
塞萊斯特沒拿奧茲鑰匙
Celeste didn't take the Oz Key.
她說把奧茲鑰匙藏在了應急響應包里 戴維克發現后拿走了
She said she hid it in her go bag. Davik had to have found the bag and taken it.
那是他在地下室被反綁的時候 還是從后門逃走的時候拿走的
When? When he was tied up in the basement? Or when he fled out the back?
你問問塞萊斯特 再問問特別行動隊 回答完全是兩個故事
You ask Celeste, you ask Ops, you get two different fucking stories.
我認識她五年了
I've known her for five years, Mason.
我比這里的任何人都了解她
I know her better than anyone here.
她沒拿
She didn't take it.
現在戴維克知道了她是臥底
And now Davik knows that she was undercover.
戴維克視她為累贅 所以會來追殺她的
She's a liability to him, and he's gonna come after her.
- 她說得對 - 我們得讓她脫身 格雷斯
She's right. We have to get her out, Grace.
她最好的選擇 就是被轉移到一個獨立的安全屋
Her best option is to relocate her to an unaffiliated safe house.
我可以聯絡一些軍情六處的聯系人
I can reach out to some MI6 contacts.
那是必須的
It'll have to do.
安德斯醒了 你們應該去審審他
Anders is awake. You should interview him.
我去吧
I'll do it.
別告訴我你們相信塞萊斯特
Do not tell me you believe Celeste.
納迪亞信她
Nadia does.
她救過納迪亞的命 納迪亞當然信她了
She saved Nadia's life. Of course she does.
塞萊斯特拿到了奧茲鑰匙
Celeste had the Oz Key.
她失聯了三個月
She went dark for three months.
然后鑰匙就消失了
Then it disappears?
她耍了我們所有人
I mean, come on, she's working all of us.
無論是堡壘 安德斯還是戴維克 她需要誰就為誰賣命
Citadel, Anders and Davik, anyone she needs to to make a buck
就為了賺錢給自己兄弟還債 救他的性命
for herself so she can pay off her brother's debt and save his life.
那我們該怎么辦
So what do we do?
我們向指揮部提出詢問
We open an inquiry with Command.
我們對她啟用后盾
We backstop her.
梅森
Mason.
我們不能就這樣刪除她的記憶
We can't just erase her memory.
她可是一級行動員 格雷斯
She's Tier-One, Grace.
她掌握堡壘的一切 你要讓她這樣回到現實中去嗎
She knows everything about Citadel. You gonna let her out in the world with that information?
她會把我們出賣給出價最高的人
She'll sell us out to the highest bidder.
我們必須清除她的記憶
- We have to wipe her clean.
指揮部甚至都還沒有批準 后盾的安全流程
- Command hasn't even approved Backstop's safety procedures yet.
這技術太新了
It's too new.
你光是提出這個建議 我就能對你施加懲罰
I could have you sanctioned for even suggesting something like that.
在你擔任主管期間 內奸搞垮了堡壘 你想被貼上這個標簽嗎
You want to be known as the director who let a mole take down the agency?
我無法授權啟用后盾
I can't authorize the backstop.
不需要你授權
You don't have to.
我們可以換個地方執行
We'd do it off-site.
不需要讓任何人知道
No one needs to know.
瞞著納迪亞 瞞著指揮部 瞞著所有人
Not Nadia. Not Command. No one.
我會處理好的
I'll take care of it.
如果最后能證明她的話是真的 我們再把她帶回來
Look, if what she says turns out to be true,
重新激活她的記憶 就好像什么事都沒發生過一樣
we'll bring her back, reactivate her memories like nothing happened.
如果是她干的呢
And what if she did it?
那就讓她處于 被啟用后盾的狀態 讓她坐牢
Then she stays backstopped. Goes to prison.
這樣一來 堡壘的機密是安全的
But Citadel's secrets are safe.
我們要怎么跟她說
What are we gonna tell her?
- 把這個戴上 - 這是什么
I'm gonna need you to put this on. - What the hell is that?
能停用你的ARC芯片 以及你在堡壘的所有證明
- It deactivates your ARC chip and the rest of your Citadel creds.
- 為什么要停用  - 我們要帶你離開這里
Why would I want that? We're getting you out of here.
戴維克知道你是誰 他會來追殺你和你兄弟的
Davik knows who you are. He's gonna come after you and your brother.
我們要把你轉移至安全屋
We're gonna relocate you to a safe house.
安全屋
A safe house?
回頭再細說 眼下來說…
There'll be time to talk later. For now...
他肯定能找到安全屋的位置
You don't think he'll be able to sniff out a safe house?
你們能找到我兄弟 他肯定也能找到
You were able to find my brother. Think about how easy it will be for them to do the same.
那你的建議是什么
-Then what do you suggest?
我不知道 但你迅速提醒了所有人 這次是你的行動
I don't know, Mason. But you're real quick to remind everyone this is your op.
既然是你的行動搞砸了 那你何不自己想辦法呢
Well, your op turned into a clusterfuck. So why don't you figure it out.
還有一個選項
There is another option.
這是一個即將推出的新程序
It's a new program soon to be rolled out.
適用于處境極為不利的一級行動員
Meant for Tier-One Operators in a worst-case scenario.
能確保他們消失
If, for whatever reason, they have to disappear.
你將被帶到墨西哥城的一個設施 在那里被注射鎮靜劑
You'll be taken to a facility in Mexico City. You'd be sedated.
在鎮靜期間 他們會對你進行兩場無痛手術
While you're under, they'll perform a pair of painless procedures
重塑你的角膜和指紋脊 幫助你隱姓埋名
to reshape your cornea and the ridges of your fingerprints to help you hide.
你以后就不是塞萊斯特格雷厄姆了 而會是另一個人
You won't be Celeste Graham anymore. You'll be someone else.
會變成戴維克永遠找不到的人
Someone that Davik can never find.
所以這算是證人轉移
So it's Witness Relocation?
沒錯 你和你兄弟都是如此
That's right. For you and your brother.
塵埃落定之后 我可以回歸我的生活嗎
And when the dust settles, I can just get back to my life?
這是保護你的最佳方式
It's the best way to protect you.
那我們就這么辦吧
Let's do it.
把她藏起來 直到我們可以撤離
Keep her hidden till we can evac.
我們不能把真相告訴納迪亞
We can't tell Nadia the truth.
搞定了嗎
Is it done?
重新安置好她了嗎
She resettled?
我親自打的電話
I made the call myself.
她正在前往安全屋的途中
She's on route to the safe house.
格雷斯 謝謝你做的一切
Thank you, Grace, for everything.
先別著急謝我
Don't thank me yet.
我們還需要找到奧茲鑰匙
We need to find the Oz Key.
是的
Yeah.
我們在找了
We're on it.
有眉目嗎
Any luck?
還沒有戴維克的跡象 我們還在找
No sign of Davik yet. We're still looking.
你覺得這個怎么樣
What do you think of this one?
很溫馨 很典雅
Uh... Cozy. Classic.
這是在俄勒岡州
Yeah, it's in Oregon.
我祖母住過的小鎮
Small town my grandmother lived in.
你給塞萊斯特 也安排了2點5個孩子嗎
Did you give her 2.5 kids, too?
你想憑空捏造生活嗎 隨你便
You want to invent a life out of thin air? Be my guest.
聽我說 如果被指揮部發現了
Look at, um, what happens if Command catches wind
你私自啟用后盾程序怎么辦
you back-channeled an unsanctioned Backstop procedure?
我可能會逃跑吧 也許我會就此安頓 過上簡單的生活
I'd have to go on the run, I guess. Maybe I'd settle down for the simple life.
那我花錢也愿意看
Yeah, I'd pay to see that.
經歷過這一天之后  不想想這棟房子嗎
After a day like today, that house?
看看這門廊 還有涼爽的夏日微風
That porch? Cool summer breeze?
天啊 你肯定連五分鐘都撐不住
Man, you wouldn't last five minutes.
謝謝你還我人情
Thanks for calling in a favor.
對 安妮梅希亞 她是個老朋友
Yeah, Ana Mejía, she's an old friend.
她用后盾創造出了非常特別的東西
She created something very special with Backstop.
我們需要毀掉塞萊斯特的藥劑
We need to destroy Celeste's vial.
永久刪除她的記憶
Erase her memories permanently.
梅森 你確定塞萊斯特是內奸嗎
Mason, are you sure that Celeste is a mole?
我知道
I know it.
你必須很篤定才行
You have to be certain.
因為以前我有一次不是很篤定 后來每天都在后悔
Because one time I wasn't and... I think about it every day.
我很篤定
I am certain.
這件事開弓沒有回頭箭
You do this, you know there's no going back.
我就是要這個效果
That's the point.
我不是說她
I'm not talking about her.
我說的是你
I'm talking about you.
加到命令里
Put in the order.
- 聽我說… - 加到命令里
- Listen to me... - Put in the order.
聽我說
Listen to me.
如果你錯怪了她
If you're wrong about her,
這件事情是不可逆的
this is not something that you can come back from.
不可逆
You can't.
一名間諜可能有一百個名字 一百張臉 一百個身份
A spy can have a hundred names, a hundred faces, a hundred identities.
但靈魂卻只有一個
But you only get one soul.
我們要不惜任何代價保護堡壘
We have to protect Citadel at all costs.
這是你告訴我的
You told me that.
那誰來保護你呢
Mm-hmm. But who's going to protect you?
不用擔心我
Don't worry about me.
堡壘后盾設施 墨西哥城
放松就好…
Just relax and breathe naturally.
卡特告訴我 塞萊斯特已經被轉移到了俄勒岡州
Carter told me Celeste has been relocated to Oregon.
梅森 謝謝你支持她
Thanks for having her back, Mason.
也謝謝你支持我
And mine.
你還好嗎
You good?
還好
Yep.
奧茲鑰匙有消息嗎
Any news on the Oz Key?
沒有
Nothing.
不是戴維克拿的
Davik didn't take it.
而且你認為也不是塞萊斯特拿的
And you don't think Celeste was the one that took it either.
什么意思
Excuse me?
我是唯一能夠訪問 堡壘所有加密通信的人
I am the only one with access to all of Citadel's encrypted communications.
那是我的工作
That's my job.
這你是知道的 對吧
You know that, right?
兄弟 我認識你十年了
I have known you a decade, brother.
我熟悉你的行為習慣和思維方式
I know your behavior patterns, how you think.
你今天的表現很不像你
You acted very out of character today.
我們處于危機之中
We were in crisis mode.
那倒是
Right.
我一開始沒想到 但我快速查詢了我們的服務器
I didn't think to at first, but I scrubbed our servers.
發現有位一級特工向特別行動隊隊長 秘密發送了一條指令
And I found that a cloaked order was given to the chief of the ops team by a Tier-One agent in secret.
而這條命令是違反協議的
And against protocol.
那位一級特工命令特別行動隊隊長 把奧茲鑰匙藏起來
That Tier-One ordered the chief to conceal the Oz Key
并在回來后交給他們
and deliver it to them on their return.
- 我知道你知道那個特工是誰 - 別說了 卡特
And I know you know who that agent was. Stop there, Carter.
那條秘密指令是納迪亞下的
Nadia gave the cloaked order.
你說過你對塞萊斯特啟用了后盾
You said that you backstopped Celeste
這樣她就不能泄露堡壘的任何秘密
so she couldn't give up any Citadel secrets,
但我認為你那樣做
but I think you did
是為了阻止我們發現她沒有罪證
that to stop us from finding out that she didn't have any.
阻止我們發現她是無辜的
She was clean.
你為了讓塞萊斯特代人受罪 所以一直對她假意懷疑
You needed to keep suspicion on Celeste to have her take the fall.
這樣一來你就能對她啟用后盾 抹去她的記憶
So you backstopped her, erased her memories.
并不是因為她對堡壘構成了威脅
Not because she was a threat to Citadel,
而是因為她會對納迪亞構成威脅
But because she would be a threat to Nadia.
因為你是在保護納迪亞
Because you are protecting Nadia.
因為雖然你很愛她…
Because even though you love her...
但你認為她可能是內奸
...you think Nadia might be a mole.
這些話你永遠不要再提
Don't you ever say those words again.
就是你干的
You-you did this.
我干了什么
What did I do?
不是你
Not you.
是她
Her.
你不能相信她
You can't trust her.
為什么不行
Why not?
納迪亞
Nadia?
《堡壘》下集精彩看點
你殺了數千名特工
You killed thousands of agents.
功勞不能都歸我一人
I can't take all the credit.
一位堡壘的特工背叛了你們所有人
A Citadel spy betrayed you all.
我已經不知道你是誰了
I don't know who you are anymore.
我們都沒有自己想象的那么清白 這你是知道的
None of us are as clean as we want to be. And you know that.
我想知道真相
You want to know the truth?
堡壘
字幕翻譯：腐哥
創意監督 羅婷婷